翻译: 晓小枫 LeE Atropa
- 学校有什么新鲜事吗  - 没有
- What's new at school? - Nothing.
没有 呃 有个盛饭的阿姨死了
Nothing! Oh, uh, one of the lunch ladies died.
校对: 约翰
在体育馆被发现的 脖子上有两个洞
They found her in the gym with, like, two holes in her neck,
血被吸干了
and all the blood drained out of her.
老天 谁能做出这种事情
Good lord! Who does something like that?
后期: Nico
显然是吸血鬼啊 胡椒呢
Obviously a vampire. W-w-where's the pepper?
等等 吸血鬼真的存在吗
Wait, what?! Vampires are real?!
压制: 三九度一
当然是真的 谁知道呢
Yes, Summer, vampires are real. Who knew?
哦对 所有人都知道 几百年了都
Oh, right, all humanity, for hundreds of years, now.
是啊 宇宙之大 无奇不有
Yeah, Summer, it's a big universe.
早点习惯吧 对吧 Rick
Get used to it. R-right, Rick?
那我们要怎么办
Well, what are we going to do?!
一直活着 到死为止
We're gonna live our lives until we die.
可能被吸血鬼吸干
Possibly by vampire.
更可能被车撞扁 或者心脏病而死
More likely auto accident or heart disease,
不过也还是可能死于吸血鬼
but possibly vampire.
外公 你能不能动用你超人的智慧
Grandpa Rick, couldn't you, like, use your superknowledge
变成青少年混进我们学校
to turn yourself into a teenager and come to our school
帮我们抓住这只吸血鬼
and help us hunt the vampire down?
呃 你这
Um-- wow.
你想得还挺详细
Yeah, pretty specific pitch, Summer.
我兴许可以变成青少年
I probably could turn myself into a teenager
混进满是青春痘和荷尔蒙
And hang out in the zit-covered, hormone-addled,
低端垃圾横行的狗屁中学
Low-stakes assworld that is high school.
Low-stakes testing在教育测试体系内是一种结果较为宽松 竞争压力小的评分系统
那我要反问一句
But here's my reverse ask--
我[哔]为什么要这么做
Why in the [bleep] would I ever do that, ever?
你凭什么要求我这么做
And how dare you even ask me that?
你这样也算是恬不知耻了
And why aren't you more ashamed of yourself?
老爸
Dad!
要知耻 宝贝
Be ashamed of yourself, sweetie.
Jerry 你意识到你刚对女儿说了什么吗
Jerry! Do you know what you just said to our daughter?
对不起 刚才我没在意
Sor-ry! I wasn't paying attention.
不在意关于吸血鬼的事情吗
To a conversation about vampires?!
很明显 我不知道是吸血鬼的事情
Clearly, I didn't know it was about vampires,
因为我就没注意
Because I wasn't paying attention,
你要是对我上点心
Which you would know, if you ever
就该知道我刚才没注意
paid attention to me!
又来了 这就进入受害者的角色了
Oh, here we go, right to the victim role.
我到底是个受害者
Am I a victim, Beth,
还是娶了一个恶毒无比
Or am I married to a mean, unfair monster
还总是伤害我的魔鬼
That always hurts me?!
老天爷
Jesus christ!
你们要是解决不了婚姻问题 赶紧离婚了事
Will you fix your marriage or get a divorce already?
我们试过一次婚姻咨询
Well, we tried a couples' therapist.
那是地球上的心理咨询
That's earth therapy.
就好比找一匹马来修旋转木马
You might as well ask a horse to fix a merry-go-round.
它再怎么想努力
I mean, he'll try his best, but mostly,
也只能被吓坏而已
He's just gonna get horrified.
我知道外星球有一个百分百成功的地方
I know about a place off-planet with a 100% success rate.
我们也想让婚姻继续啊 如果我们能的话
Well, we want to make it work, if we can.
- 但是  - 那就这么定了
- It's just..  - Then it's settled.
不用打包衣物了
No need to pack.
出发出发出发
Let's go, go, go, go!
你觉得老爸和老妈
Do you think mom and dad are, you know,
会离婚吗
Gonna get a divorce?
这么想想还是可以的
I think it's okay to dream, Morty.
我去做几根木钉
I'm gonna go make some wooden stakes.
瑞克与莫蒂
电波诚译
第二季 第七集
我在婚四所给你们定了两天的强化治疗
I booked you for a two-day intensive at Nuptia Four,
他家是银河系里最好的婚姻咨询机构
The galaxy's most successful couples' counseling institute.
他们甚至可以挽救
They could save the marriage of a dog
狗和巧克力的婚姻
and a bar of dark chocolate.
两个色情影星的婚姻
They could save the marriage of a porn star and a porn star.
至少我是愿意试一试的
Well, I know I'm ready to try whatever it takes.
你这话是说我不愿意咯
Which clearly implies that I'm not.
又不是要比什么 Beth
It's not a competition, Beth.
你打赢嘴仗的策略就是
Oh is that how you're gonna try to win,
暗示说我太争强好胜是吧
By implying I'm competitive?
难道你不是吗
If the shoe fits.
- 是你妈个头  - 呵呵
- My shoe fits up your ass. - You wish!
你们咨询愉快 周四见
Okay, have fun. See ya Thursday!
好疼
Oh!
这老混蛋
Jerk.
别这么说我爸
Don't insult my father.
有了他的基因 我们的孩子才只是半蠢而不是全蠢
He's the reason our kids are only half-stupid.
哈 你刚才说自己
Ha! You just called yourself --
我懂了
Oh.
- Smith夫妇吗  - 是的
- Beth and Jerry Smith? - Yes.
我是Glaxo Slimslom
I'm Glaxo Slimslom.
欢迎来到婚四所
Welcome to Nuptia Four.
这里能解决你们婚姻的烦恼
Your marriage can rest easy now.
Jerry 坐在这里 把这个戴上
Jerry, go ahead and sit there and put this on.
这个仪器可以扫描提取你大脑中
This machine isolates the part of the subject's brain
关于你对配偶的感知
Containing all perceptions of its romantic partner.
现在扫描Jerry对Beth的感知
And we will now render Jerry's perception of Beth
并具体化为人工生物的形象
With artificial biological life.
这个有意思
Interesting.
这是什么玩意 收回你的想法
What the hell is that?! Take that back!
你竟然把我想成这样
You do not think that about me!
我什么都没做啊
I didn't do anything!
他们把我的想法扫描出来了
They scanned it out of my brain.
我能收回那个想法吗
Can I take it back?
没什么好后悔的
There's nothing to regret.
我们就是要处理这些无意识 不健康的想法
We're dealing with unconscious, unhealthy thoughts.
该你了
Beth.
现在扫描Beth对Jerry的感知
Now, we scan for Beth's perceptions of Jerry.
使劲扫 他于我与死人无异
Scan hard. He's dead to me.
什么对你来说都是死物吧
Everything's dead to you.
- 你再说一遍  - 没事
- What? - Nothing.
好好看看 一边哭去吧
Read it and weep, bitch.
你们都看到我是什么意思了吧
Does everybody see what I mean?
你们两个的意思 大家都看得很清楚
I think we all see what you both mean.
吸血鬼的事有什么进展吗
Any leads on the vampire?
别这样 我是说
No, Summer! I mean, you know,
我们就别再在意这事情了
I think it might be time that we just l-let it go.
你觉得这没什么大不了
Oh, so, now, you're too cool for this,
就因为外公也这么想吗
Just because grandpa Rick is?
不是因为这个 宇宙实在太大了
It's not that, it's just that the universe
没必要在意这么微不足道的事
is a little too big to care about something so small.
啊
Aah!
你们好啊 小海辛们
What up, my Helsings?
范海辛是著名的吸血鬼猎人
谁想来猎杀吸血鬼 哈哈
Who wants to hunt a vampire? Ha ha ha!
Rick 你 你怎么
Rick? How-- how did you--
我刚才无聊来着 然后想起来
Yeah, I got bored and then, I remembered,
今早我回绝了Summer 然后我寻思
This morning, how I blew Summer off, and I thought,
干嘛非得跟个老混蛋似的
Hey, why are you such a grumpy douche, Rick?
赶紧到车库里
Go to the garage,
把自己的思维传输到少年的克隆体
transfer your mind into a younger clone of yourself,
然后加入到年轻人的狂欢里吧
and get embroiled in some youthful hijinks,
有什么大不了的
What's the BFD?
所以我就来了 我是小Rick
So here I am. I'm tiny Rick!
好 好吧
O-o-okay.
你来了就好 Rick
Well, it's good you're here, Rick.
我们自己肯定搞不定
I was pretty sure we didn't have what it takes
那个吸血的东西的
to deal with a bloodsucker on our own.
别妄自菲薄 Summer
Don't short-sell yourself, Summer.
你完全能做到 但是我们[哔]组队的话
You got everything it takes. But it'll still be fun
还是很有趣啊 小Rick[哔]无敌
To do this as a [bleep] team, mother[bleep] tiny Rick!
天呐 Toby Matthews来了
Oh, my god, Toby Matthews!
嗨 我是小Rick 我新来的
Hey, Toby. I'm tiny Rick. I'm new.
别欺负我哦 哈哈 开玩笑的
Hey oh-- go easy on me. Ha ha. Just kiddin'.
我就喜欢你这种直接的性格
I like your straightforward style.
你这实验服的行头挺酷的
And that lab coat's pretty cool.
好啊Summer
Summer.
他知道我的名字
He knew my name!
他怎么会不知道 你长这么美
Why wouldn't he? You're great!
但是我们还是小心为妙
But, listen, just be careful.
我们不能排除任何人是吸血鬼的嫌疑
We can't rule anybody out as the vampire,
男神也不行
Not even the dreamboats.
讨厌
Stop, tiny Rick.
跟孙子孙女杀吸血鬼去啦
Huntin' a vampire with my grandkids!
小Rick[哔]无敌
[bleep]tiny Rick!
下一步是观察你们的构造体
The next step is to watch your mythologues
观察他们之间的互动 "意外"的是
interact together and, uh-- big surprise--
场面从来都不好看
It's never pretty.
这是Gloompfschs夫妇
Here we have Garrrh and Zharbidar Gloompfschs,
换种说法
Or, should I say, here we have the way
这是这对夫妇对对方的感知
Garrrh and Zharbidar perceive each other.
很明显
As we can all see,
这根本不是他们本来的样子
This is hardly the real Garrrh and Zharbidar.
不过这很好 因为在他们脑海里
Which is good, because the relationship
他们的婚姻关系不仅丑恶
In their heads is not only ugly,
而且难以维系
It's unsustainable.
你们可能已经学到了重要的一课
You may already be learning something important--
我们看到的所有婚姻关系都各不相同
All of these relationships are different,
都不真实 而且没有一对能行的通
None of them are real, and none of them work.
我们并不是对方时常认为的魔鬼模样
We are not the monsters we sometimes see each other as,
因为我们是真实的 我们是协调的
Because we are real and we are functional.
正因为此 我们比这些怪物好多了
That's what makes us better than them.
我们能解决问题
We can find solutions.
能相互适应
We can adapt.
能相互交流
We can communicate.
最重要的是
And, most importantly,
我们能相互合作
We can work together.
虽然颇有坎坷 最后终于苦尽甘来
Well, it was a tough adventure, but it paid off --
学校里没有吸血鬼啦
Our school is vampire-free!
没想到Feratu教练竟然是吸血鬼
Man, who would've suspected coach Feratu?
这个名字出自著名的吸血鬼诺斯费拉图
你们做得很好 功不可没
You did great, guys. Couldn't have done it without ya.
我们要为自己感到骄傲
You know, we-- w-we should be proud of ourselves.
我们杀了一个吸血鬼 同时干掉一个体育老师
We killed a vampire and a gym teacher.
哈哈 也算一石二鸟
Ha ha ha. Talk about two-for-one, right?!
你原本的身体是
So, how, exactly, is your old body
怎么在这里面维持生命的啊
living in there, grandpa Rick?
这是高压氧量子液体
Oh, you know, hyperbaric quantum fluid,
乱七八糟的东西
That kind of thing.
可以保存生物组织
It preserves living tissue.
也没多少东西要保存的了
Not that there was much to preserve.
你看那皮包骨跟木乃伊似的
Look at that mummy! Ha! Ha ha!
我该回到那老家伙的身体里了
And I guess it's time for me to get back inside the old-timer.
天呐Toby Matthews问我父母在不在家
Oh, my god. Toby Matthews is asking if my parents
还问我能不能开派对
Are still out of town and if we can have a party!
真棒 Summer 你看我上午说什么来着
All right, way to go, Summer! What did I tell you?
他还问小Rick会不会来
Ohh! He's asking if tiny Rick will be here.
Summer 我转念一想
Well, you know what, Summer?
你告诉他 小Rick会过去的
Tell him tiny Rick will be here!
让他带点酒来
And tell him to bring some brews!
真的吗 你 你会以小Rick的身份留下
For real? Y-y-y-you would stay as tiny Rick,
就为了留下来开派对
Just so we can have a party?
是啊 多一晚又有什么关系
Hell, yeah! What's one more night?
再说这老家伙在这儿 谁能尽兴啊
And who can have fun with this old bastard hanging around, huh?
Wubby lubby doob doob
Wubby lubby doob doob!
小Rick
Tiny Rick!
接下来 这边是Beth和Jerry Smith
Moving on. Now, we have beth and jerry smith
来自地一球行星
From the planet e-arth.
我的心跳得很厉害
My heart is pounding.
一定会很棒
This is gonna be great.
地一球的两性关系比较简单
The e-arth relationships are simpler.
它是一个原始星球 所以他们的失调状态
It's a primitive planet, so their dysfunctions are oh --
等等 发生了什么
W-wait, what? What's going on?
Smith夫妇的构造体在哪
Where are the smith mythologues?
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
- 天啊  - 守住那个牢房
- Oh, my god. - Secure the cell!
谁想参观一下礼品店 很有趣的
Uh, hey! You know what's fun? Our gift shop.
我们何不有序地前往
Why don't we proceed in an orderly --
我的老天
Oh, dear god, no.
他们是互利共生的
They're codependent!
快跑
Run!
真的 你真的很会驾驭
Oh, yeah, yeah, you really know how to
- 蓝色的衣服啊  - 真的吗
- sport that color blue. - Really?
- 你今天真的很美  - 我的天啊
- You're looking real good. - Oh, my god.
- 你好 Morty  - 你好啊 Jessica
- Hey, morty. Oh, hey - hey, Jessica.
那个 小Rick是你的亲兄弟还是表的
So, is tiny Rick your brother or cousin, or...?
都不是 我外公把他的意识
No, my grandpa just transferred
转移到他自己的克隆体上了
His consciousness into a clone of himself
这样他就可以来我们学校了
So he could be in our high school.
帅气
Cool.
快来看 小Rick在弹吉他
Hey, tiny Rick's playing guitar.
各位朋友
All right, everybody.
下一首来自我的内心
This next one's coming straight from the heart.
想到哪儿唱到哪儿 现场发挥的歌词
Making the lyrics up right off the top of my head.
*放我出来 你所见的*
*Let me out, What you see*
*只是一个假的驱壳*
*is not the  same person as me*
*我的生活是个谎言 我不是你望着的那个人*
*My life's a lie, I'm not who you're looking at*
*放我出来 给我自由 我已年迈*
*Let me out, set me free,I'm really old *
*这不是真正的我*
*This isn't me*
*我的身体在大缸里渐渐死亡*
*My real body's slowly dying in a vat*
*有人听到我的呐喊吗 有人明白我吗*
*Is anybody listening, can anyone understand*
*别再傻盯着我了 救救我吧*
*Stop Looking at me like that and actually help me*
*救我 救救我 我要死了*
*Help! Help me, I'm gonna die*
我是小Rick 谢谢捧场
Tiny Rick! Thanks, everybody!
这家伙太赞了
This guy's amazing!
- 我爱小Rick   - 帅飞了
- I love tiny Rick! - Bad ass.
搞什么[哔]
What the [bleep]?
就是 你们这机构怎么搞的
Yeah, I know! What kind of operation are you running?
我们 你们两夫妇是什么的婚姻关系啊
Us?! What the hell kind of relationship do you have?!
真好 怪在我们的头上
Oh, right, blame this on us.
对 没错 我就怪在你们头上
Okay, uh, I can and I am!
你们的恶魔化构造体居然在合作
Your demonized mythologizations of each other are cooperating.
这不是好事吗
Isn't that good?
才不是 糟透了
No. No! It's bad!
你们的婚姻是我见过最糟的
You have the single worst marriage I've ever witnessed.
根本不应该存在
It shouldn't exist!
你们根本完全彻底不应该在一起
You should never, ever, ever, have gotten together
我还很不懂你们是怎么以及为什么
And I do not understand how, or why,
会走到一起
You would ever stay together.
你这婚姻咨询也太烂了吧
Well, this is just bad couples' therapy.
可不是嘛
Totally.
等等我们
Wait for us!
位置只够再多一人了
There's only room for one more.
我是心理咨询师 我跟他们说说
I'm a therapist. I'll talk to them.
他们不是咨询师 马上走
They're not therapists. Go, go, go!
肯定有办法联系上爸爸的
There's gotta be a way to contact my dad.
我们找个控制室什么的
Let's find a control room or something.
Beth 快来看看
Beth! You'll want to see this.
这是什么
What is it?
这是个小型可拆卸面板
It's a small, hinged panel
后面有一些空间
With a tiny amount of space behind it.
如果你也能找到一个
If you can find one, too,
接下来几个小时或几天我们就安全了
We should be safe for hours, maybe days!
Jerry 你在这里待好
You stay put, Jerry.
我去求救 假如我能活着的话
I'll send help, if I make it.
你不找个地方自己躲起来吗
You don't want to find your own little hatch?
Jerry 我相信你独自躲好的话
Jerry, I believe that, if you hide by yourself,
你可以活下去
You might survive and I believe I,
同时我也相信 我独自也能逃出这里
By myself, have a shot of getting out of here,
但是我们两人一起
But the two of us, together?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能那个心理医生是对的
Look, maybe the shrink was right.
祝你好运
Good luck.
你给我听好了
All right, now, you listen to me.
其实不听也可以
Oh! Or don't.
别 求你了
Hey! Don't! Please!
天啊 别过来
Oh, god, oh, god, oh, god!
我明白我以前说过什么
Now, I know I've said, in the past,
数学很重要 确实是
That math is important -- and it is! --
我还认为 总有一天 你们会回想起
But I also think that, one day, you'll all look back
跟小Rick和Morty做同学的日子
On being in high school with tiny Rick and Morty,
因为听说他们昨晚搞了一个超级棒的派对
Who I hear had a great party last night.
那么 下课
So, class dismissed.
今天放你们假
You've got the day off!
干的好 Goldenfold先生
All right! Good work, mr. Goldenfold!
没错 到外面转转 多读书
Yeah, get outside. Read a book.
Danielle 涂点防晒霜
Put on some sunscreen, Danielle!
Summer 你好 上衣真漂亮
Hey, what's up, Summer? Ooh, nice top.
谢谢你 小Rick 你觉得
Thanks. Tiny rick, you think you might be
你今晚可以回到老的身体里去吗
Getting back into your old body tonight?
不行喔 今晚是舞会之夜
No can do. Tonight's the big dance
Morty还会带Jessica出席 他需要这架小僚机
And Morty's bringing Jessica. He needs his tiny wing man.
小Rick
Tiny Rick!
今晚不行的话要等到什么时候
Okay, but if not tonight, when?
不清楚 等我想回去了
I don't know. When I feel like it?
你别这么咄咄逼人的
Damn, girl! You need to chill out!
这件事是你先想出来的
This whole thing was your idea, in the first place,
现在又是你想尽快结束
And, now, you're trying to rush it along.
可不是嘛 我喜欢高中
Yeah, and you know what? I like high school.
我喜欢跟大家玩 小Rick万岁
I like hanging out. Tiny rick!
但是如果喜欢这样生活的人不是真正的你呢
But what if the you that likes it isn't you?
别傻了 Summer
Oh, Summer!
这就是有个年轻驱壳的Rick
It's just Rick in a younger body.
会 会 会 会
What's the -- what's -- what's -- what's --
会有什么问题啊
What's the -- what's the problem?
看看他的画 Morty
Look at his art, Morty.
我最近走情绪摇滚风
I've got an emo streak.
也算是我这么酷炫的部分原因
It's part of what makes me so rad.
为什么这里写着"救救我 Morty和Summer"
Why does it say "Help me morty and summer!"?
Summer 这是画的题目
Come on, Summer, that's the title of the art.
为什么<霹雳游侠>叫霹雳游侠
Why was knight rider called knight rider?
<霹雳游侠> 80年代电视剧
车的名字明明是Kitt 被人开的不是Michael Knight.
The car's name was kitt. Nobody rode Michael Knight.
男主名叫Michael Knight
你想多了 Summer 我是小Rick
You're overthinking it, summer. I'm tiny rick!
外公 我觉得 你把意识
Grandpa, I think that, when you put your mind
放进这个年轻的躯体了
Into this body's young brain,
他就做年轻人做的事
It did what young brains do --
这副躯体把坏的想法压在心底
It shoved the bad thoughts into the back
掩藏起来
And put a wall around them.
但那些想法属于真正的Rick
But those bad thoughts are the real Rick.
你已经年迈的事实
The fact that you're old, the fact that
我们终有一天会死的事实
We're all going to die, one day, the fact that
宇宙很大 任何事都很渺小的事实
The universe is so big, nothing in it matters,
这些事实才造就真正的你
Those facts are who you are.
所以真正的Rick被困住了
So you're trapped in there and you can only
你只能通过小Rick的青少年焦虑表现出来
Come out in the form of tiny rick's teen angst!
Summer 我听说
Well, Summer, I hear
Toby Matthews 不喜欢神经兮兮瞎分析的女孩
Toby Matthews isn't into psycho chicks.
没有人喜欢这类女孩
Can't think of anyone that is.
舞会上见啦 兔崽子们 小Rick万岁
I'll see you mother at the dance! Tiny rick!
Morty 你要帮我
Morty, you have to help me!
Summer 他很开心 我也很开心
Summer, he's happy! I'm happy!
这就是你的目的吗
I-I-is that why you're doing this,
不让我们开心
You don't want me and rick to be happy?
不是
No.
那就把你这些逼事儿收拾收拾
Well, then get your shit together!
全收起来放到书包里
Get it all together and put it in a backpack.
所有的逼事儿 好好收拾收拾
All your shit, so it's together.
如果你想把它们带走
And if you gotta take it somewhere,
就快带走 懂吗
Take it somewhere, you know?
带到逼事儿店卖了
Take it to the shit store and sell it
或者在逼事儿博物馆展览 我不管
O-or put it in a shit museum. I don't care what you do!
总之 收拾好你的破逼事儿
You just gotta get it together.
收拾好
Get your shit together.
别过来
Get back!
等等 不是吧
Wait, for real?
你是Beth对我的看法
You're how Beth sees me?
天啊
Oh, my god.
转过身去
Turn around!
我说转过身去
I said turn around!
Beth怎么会这样想我
How can beth have these thoughts about me?!
那个狗眼看人低的贱人
That judgmental monster bitch!
我可不接受
I'm not taking this.
我想知道我的妻子在哪
I want to know where my wife is.
你要协助我
You are going to help me.
停 别再这样了
No! Nobody's doing that!
别动
Stay.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
更多Jerry
Jerrys.
你想要Jerry
You want jerry?
我都不想要Jerry
I don't even want jerry.
我要很多Jerry
I want Jerrys.
一支Jerry军队
An army.
Jerry军队
An army of jerrys.
他的顺从的价值都浪费在你身上了
The value of his subservience is wasted on you.
我要利用它来征服宇宙
I will use it to dominate the universe.
天啊 Jerry肯定觉得
Ah ha ha. Boy, Jerry must think
我得多愚蠢 你才会这么蠢
I'm pretty stupid, for you to be this stupid.
你把我那个笨蛋丈夫放在
Wouldn't it make more sense to put my dumbass husband
这椅子上不更合理吗
In this chair, so you can make
你就可以制造一堆厉害的自己了
An army of your bad-ass self?
我永远独一无二
There could never be more than one of me.
我是世上最强最聪明的生物
I'm the strongest, smartest being alive
因为那就是Jerry所认为的你
Because jerry thinks you're that much stronger
比你要聪明和强大的程度
And smarter than you are!
好吧 嗷
Okay, ouch.
Morty Jessica 干嘛呢
Morty, Jessica, what's up?
快来欣赏一下的我的自创舞蹈
Check out the new dance I made up.
叫做"啊 放我出去"
It's called "Ooh let me out!"
*放我出来 放我出来 我不是在跳舞*
*Let me out. Let me out. This is not a dance.*
*我乞求帮助 我需要帮助*
*I'm begging for help, I'm screaming for help*
*请放我出来吧*
*Please come let me out*
*放我出来 放我出来 我不是在跳舞*
*Let me out, let me out, this is not a dance*
*我乞求帮助 我需要帮助*
*I'M I'm beging for help, I'm screaming for help*
*请放我出来*
*Please come let me out*
*我在一个车库的大缸中正在死去*
*I'm dying in a vat in a garage*
好吧 最后那段真挺怪的
Okay, that last part was really weird.
也许Summer这回说得对
Maybe summer's on to something here.
我不知道 这事挺好玩的
I don't know. It was fun.
你想来段慢舞不
You want to slow dance?
小Rick 一如既往的舞技高超呀
Tiny rick, hey, great dancing as usual.
能占用你一点时间不
Moment of your time?
小Rick 我来找你谈话
Tiny rick, this conversation
让我心碎得一片一片的
Is gonna break my heart wide open.
你是个很棒的学生 而且你是个
You're a great student and the fact that
思想植入克隆身体内的80岁老人这事
You're an 80-year-old man in a clone body,
对我来说从来不是事
It never bothered me.
但是这里有这么个事
But this here is another matter.
认得这个么
You recognize this?
我们收到线报说这个是从你的更衣柜里找到的
We got a tip it was in your locker.
是吧 现在 因为体育老师确实是个吸血鬼
Yeah, now, because the gym coach was a vampire,
学校董事会觉得很丢脸
The school board is embarrassed
并且决定不会公之于众 但是
And won't take it public, however,
他们不能容忍学生杀掉老师这件事
They can't have students killin' teachers.
我这回必须得开除你了 小瑞
I gotta expel you for this one, tr.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Summer 我被开除了
I just got expelled, summer!
哦 所以说你没必要保持年轻了吧
Oh! So I guess there's no need to stay young.
我的上衣
My top!
去你的上衣
Screw your top!
你告我密 我可是小Rick
You ratted on me?! I'm tiny rick!
好吧 是这样的 但是是因为我爱你
Fine! Yes! Because I love you
我想救你一命
And I'm trying to save your life!
高中就是我的命
High school is my life!
Summer Smith是个[哔]呆子神经病
Summer Smith is a [beep] psycho nerd
而且她刚刚害我被开除啦
And she just got me kicked out of school!
切
Boo!
Summer 我还以为你很酷呢
Summer, I thought you were cool!
我很抱歉 好么
I'm sorry, okay?
你怎么可以这么婊啊
How can you be such a bitch?
我的天啊 Morty
Oh, my god, Morty.
你姐姐背叛了小Rick
Your sister crossed tiny Rick?
论什么叫自毁
Talk about self-destructive.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿 那边那个Jerry迷
Hey, jerry-lover!
要不要尝尝本尊的厉害
How about a taste of the real thing?
Jerry
Jerry!
有我在你就别想得逞
Not on my watch.
有了
That's it!
Beth 是我 你的丈夫
Beth, it's me, your husband!
我来救你了
I'm here to save you.
不然我就不叫Jerry Smith
Or my name isn't Jerry Smith!
- 啊哈  - 是的
- Aha! - yes!
Jerry Smith
Jerry Smith!
- 耶 来了  - 啊哈
- Yeah, here. -aha!
好吧 你狠
Okay, fair enough.
说晚安吧 老头
Say goodnight, old man.
- 你干嘛呢  - 快放下
- What the hell are you doing?! - Put it down!
Summer 你这个婊子
Summer, you bitch!
不许这么跟她说话 她是你孙女
Don't talk to her that way! She's your granddaughter!
我不需要什么孙女 我是小Rick
I don't need a granddaughter! I'm tiny ri-I-ck!
她是我姐姐 如果小Rick对待我姐姐
She's my sister! And if tiny rick
要是这么混蛋的话
Is gonna be an asshole to my sister, then,
你知道么 你你你还不如变老吧
You know, y-y-you may as well be old again.
你觉得你特厉害 是吧 Morty
You think you're tough, huh, Morty?
你能怎么样 我可是小Rick
What are you gonna do? I'm tiny rick.
我是你们学校最酷的学生
I'm the coolest kid in your school.
你怎么让我对你言听计从啊
How are you gonna just make me do whatever you say, huh?
我能做真正的Rick会做的事
I'm gonna do what real rick would do if he was here—
我要揍你
I'm gonna kick your ass!
Rick我知道你在
Rick, I know you're in there!
我知道你想要出来
I know you're trying to get out!
就这样Morty 按住他
That's it, morty! Hold him down!
听 小Rick
Listen to it, tiny rick.
听 艾略特史密斯的歌
Listen to Elliott Smith.
不要
Ugh! No!
感受他的感受
Feel what he's feeling.
不 天呐
Ugh! Noooooooo! God!
哦天呐 生命是什么
Oh, God, what is life?
如此有才华的人为何英年早逝
How can someone so talented die so young
年轻是什么
What is being young?
我不年轻了 我老了
I'm not young. I'm old.
我 我会死
I'm— I'm gonna die.
我的身体不是真的
My body isn't real.
Morty Summer
Morty! Summer!
是我 是Rick
It's me! It's Rick!
真Rick
Regular Rick!
Rick 我们怎么把你放回你的身体里
Rick! How do we get you back into your body?
好吧仔细听着 那个大桶的仪表盘上
Okay, listen carefully. There's a set of diodes
有一套二极管 有一个蓝的 有一个红的连到
On the vat's control panel, a blue one and a red one to.
哦天呐 这是个什么世道啊
Oh, god, what kind of world is this?
不是我要出生在这个世界上的 把那个
I didn't ask to be born. I need you to connect
蓝的连在我的左太阳穴 然后红的
The blue one to my left temple and the red one to—
为什么大家都不是真的喜欢我
Why doesn't anyone really like me?
集中注意力 姥爷 快把那破电线
Focus, grandpa! Just put the stupid
连我头上 我讨厌做个青少年
Wires on my head! I hate being a teenager!
Jerry 你是掰不动金属的
Jerry, you can't bend metal.
那就造一个能掰动的我
Then make a me that can!
我这边看着你根本掰不动金属呢
How can I do that while I'm watching you
我怎么想象啊
Totally fail to bend metal?
这就是咱们的Beth
Good old beth!
冷如机器 毒如蛇蝎
The mind of a robot and the heart of an insect!
不许这么说她
Don't talk that way about her.
什么
What?
啊 疼啊
Oh, it hurts!
哦 天呐
Oh, god.
停下
Stop.
这个形象让我很不悦
This representation displeases me.
天呐 你是怎么
Good lord. How did you...?
这个 我感觉 在你心目中的
Well, I had a feeling that, in your mind,
那个理想的我应该足够聪明到可以
The ideal version of me is one smart enough
在心里把你当做
To see you as...
女神
A goddess.
你现在可不是什么蠢虫子了 是吧
Not such a stupid worm now, are you?
亲爱的 在有关于你的自尊心的课题上
Honey, when it comes to the subject of your ego,
我可称得上史蒂芬[哔]霍金
I'm Stephen [beep] Hawkinson.
我去 应该是 算了
Ugh, it's -- never mind.
我爱你
I love you.
Rick 裤子
Rick! Pants!
我靠
Holy shit!
谢谢了孩子们 你们解决了问题
Thanks, kids. You figured it out.
好吧  其实是Summer解决的
Well, summer did.
真是挺怪的 Morty你能那么愿意为了个妞
Kind of weird that you were that willing
把我的整个存在给卖了
To sell my existence out for some trim, Morty.
- 什么  - 裤子
- What?! - Pants!
但是听着 我原谅你们俩 知道为什么不
But listen— I forgive you both because you know what?
我今天学到了重要的东西
I learned, today, something important—
青少年的心就是它自己最大的敌人
The teenage mind is its own worst enemy.
哦 我还学到了
Oh, I also learned this...
凤凰计划根本不可靠 不像我想的那样
Operation phoenix is not the fallback I thought it would be.
看来一切都要从头开始了
I guess it's back to the drawing board.
哦天呐
Oh, my god!
哦我的天呐 穿裤子去
Oh, my god. Put some pants on!
穿裤子
Put pants on.
外公回来了 宝贝
Grandpa's back, baby!
外公
Grandpa's --
唉 我还得去接你们的爸妈
Oh, man, I gotta pick up your parents.
他俩快把我电话打爆了
They have been blowin' me up.
走前再砍一刀
One last swing for the road!
我的天呐 穿点衣服行么
For the love of god, get dressed!
所以说 你怎么想的 你想
So, what do you think? You wanna
咱俩再维持这段婚姻一段时间不
Keep this marriage going a while longer?
至少也得坚持到Morty高中毕业呀
At least until morty has graduated high school.
哦 嗯
Oh. Mm.
啊哈 你看 我怎么说的来着
Aha, you see? What did I tell you two?
有效果吧
It worked.
你知道么Rick 我想 从某种程度上来讲 可能
You know what, rick? I guess, in a way, maybe—
没兴趣 上车
Already lost interest. Get in the car.
我一整天都待在一个孩子的体内
I've been inside a kid all day and, now,
我现在都能听到我骨头相互摩擦的声音
I can feel my bones scraping each other.
让你有点心理准备
Uh, just so you're prepared,
车库里有一堆我的尸体
There's a bunch of dead mes in the garage.
哈 听起来咱们的故事有一个共通的主题了
Huh! Sounds like our stories were connected by a theme.
不可能 Jerry
Not really, jerry.
有可能就是表面上的联系而你的脑子觉得这是主题上的联系
Probably a cosmetic connection your mind mistakes for thematic.
哦
Oh.
老Rick  毁掉一切
Old rick! Ruinin' everything!
主人
Master.
说
Speak.
Feratu教练的真身
Coach Feratu's presence
被人类识破了
Was discovered by the humans.
他被杀掉了
He has been destroyed.
没事
No bother.
凡人们很快就会
The mortals shall soon—
不好意思 你说谁来着
I'm sorry, what did you say his name was?
- Feratu教练  - Feratu教练
- Coach Feratu.  - Coach Feratu.
那是他的真名么 他的吸血鬼真名
That was his real name, like his actual vampire name?
不不不不 他的吸血鬼命叫Balik Alistane
No no no no. His vampire name was balik alistane.
他怎么[哔]给自己起这么个名啊
Why the [beep] would he name himself
跟那么有名的吸血鬼电影一样的 他演什么戏呢
after a famous vampire movie? Was he doing a bit?
我不知道 我不洁的主人
I do not know, your unholiness.
耶稣[哔]基督啊
Jesus [beep] Christ.
从现在开始不许再有这些自以为机智乱起名的破事
From now on, no more of this clever-name bullshit.
吸血鬼假装人类的时候
When a vampire is pretending to be a human,
他们只能给自己起像什么
They can just call themselves
Alan Jefferson之类的名
Alan Jefferson or something like that.
真有病 是不是
It's crazy, right?
我是说 我这么做很混蛋么
I mean, am I being an asshole?
好吧 我觉得屋里每一个人
Okay, I feel like everybody in the room
都跟看着个扫兴鬼 一样看着我
Is looking at me like I'm the buzzkill.
我不是
I'm not?
好 挺好 很好
Good. Okay. Great.
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组